[Music]
what would it sound like if we were to
rotate regular polygons on the circle of
fifths and every time a vertex of the
rotating polygon crosses over a note
that note gets
played the simplest regular polygon is
an equilateral triangle and on the
circle of fifths an equilateral triangle
forms an augmented Triad that is the
root the major thir and the sharp fifth
or augmented fifth so when we rotate
this triangle we'll just get a series of
augmented
[Music]
chords if we rotate the triangle
clockwise instead we get the same chords
just played in the opposite order which
is true for all of the polygons will be
rotating
[Music]
with a square we get another symmetrical
chord a diminished seventh chord which
is just minor thirds stacked on top of
each other
[Music]
all
the Pentagon is the first shape where
the vertices don't all land on notes at
the same
time before rotating this shape and
listening to the results take a guess as
to what you think it will play pause the
video if you want when I first ran this
I was a bit surprised by the
result
[Music]
it's playing a chromatic scale all 12
notes in ascending
order add this to your list of useless
but interesting
[Music]
facts
a hexagon plays all the notes of the two
whole tone scales as alternating
[Music]
chords
a heptagon does the same thing as the
Pentagon but in the opposite order and a
bit faster relative to the rotation
[Music]
speed
an octagon plays the same diminished
chords as the square but twice as fast
relative to the rotation speed and in
the opposite
[Music]
direction
a nonagon or nine-sided polygon plays
augmented chords but three times as fast
as the triangle and in the opposite
[Music]
direction
the decagon plays the chromatic scale at
the same speed as the Pentagon except
that it plays two chromatic scales
simultaneously a trone
[Music]
apart
the hend deagon or 11-sided polygon
plays either the circle of fourths or
fifths whichever one is in the opposite
direction of the
[Music]
rotation
and finally I'll leave you with arguably
the worst sounding polygon a do
[Music]
deagon as you might have already figured
out this will just play all 12 notes
[Music]
simultaneously
d